[Music]
podcasts our very first one my name is
Juan M I am a community manager here at
Stack Overflow and I am joined by two of
my colleagues welcome Abby welcome John
let me say hello to you all and then
give you guys an opportunity to tell us
a little bit about who you are so why
don't we just do that now Abby let me
pass her on to you how are you today I'm
doing great I'm doing great thanks how
are you I'm doing okay John how are you
today I am also doing well I actually
have a little bit of a cold but that's
probably nicer doctor sorry to hear
sorry to hear well in the interest of
keeping things brief and concise and
super informative let's let me ask you
guys first to to tell us a little bit
about yourself so that our listeners
know who we are and why we want to do
this thing that we're doing right now so
every when we start with you totally
yeah so my name's Abby has once said if
you are listening as a member of the
stack exchange or Stack Overflow
community you might have seen me around
as airboat that's kind of my internet
street name I guess hair boat I'll tell
you that story sometime I work with the
community team and the support team here
at Stack Overflow mainly I think my role
with the community team is providing
emotional support we did it from time to
time we all we all get there so yes I
help out I help out in the feelings
Department with the community managers
and yeah kind of go from there so that's
what I'm interested in in what I do
helping these guys be as effective as
they can and help the communities as
much as they can
yeah that's great thanks Abby John let's
pass over you John tell us a little bit
about yourself so I'm a plain old
community manager I guess technically
I've got a title of community product
manager but that basically means I'm
writing meta posts and helping people
out on the site and thinking about how
the site can work better
and handling interpersonal issues that
come up on the site and pointing
moderators and while these days running
elections for moderators and just just a
grab bag full of stuff one what what do
you do here well thanks for asking Jeff
I am also a community manager I manage a
team here internally and we're looking
at our international sites or
international sac overflow sites for
those of you who don't know we do have a
Japanese a Russian a Portuguese and a
Spanish site for developers and coders
from all over the world to come and ask
questions to learn share and grow this
is a place for them to not only get
answers to questions they have but to
build community to get to know other
developers who are interested in the
same things that they are I'm also
taking a look at the sites for our Stack
Exchange network which is all of our
communities that are not Stack Overflow
which is a lot it's over 170 and so I'm
taking a look at those communities as
well saying about different ways to to
continue to engage our users to bring
value to to these communities to grow
them as well and so these are two things
that I'm currently in charge of right
now and that brings me to why we're
doing this podcast so this is a this is
a yeah it's a collaboration between us
all and what what we're interested in as
community manager is just people who are
are wanting to grow and and mature our
communities right the relationship
between our users we want people to know
not just about the site's we want them
to know about the inside the inside
stuff the inside scoop so to speak the
meta of it all and so you know we
thought it'd be a good idea to have some
topics to be able to discuss these
things and and be able to talk about
them in a candid way and so let me let
me start off with it with you John what
are what are some goals that you would
have for for this podcast so I kind of
going back in time I was part of Stack
Overflow in the beginning and one of the
things that happened was joel and jeff
built the website basically by
posting stuff on their blogs and then
reading the comments and then later on
they went and did something called user
voice which is a feedback thing and so
some of you may remember way back in the
prehistory basically of the site there
was this user voice thing and one of the
things I wrote a bit of feedback I asked
for a place to have met at a discussion
and I didn't think user voice was the
right place I wanted somewhere where
people could talk about the site and and
it that was part of the reason we ended
up with meta stack overflow yeah you
know initially so it's my fault it's my
fault
in part it's on record you can take no
it is on record you can if you go to the
blog post that announces it my little
user voice thing was quoted there which
was kind of a surprise I didn't realize
Jeff had paid any attention to that and
that's part of the reason why we have
meta right is because we want we want to
give people the idea that we're paying
attention to them and and that's been
hard right it's it's as the site has
grown as our company has grown it's been
harder and harder to give people that
sense of feedback and so this is I think
a piece of the puzzle this podcast yeah
this good ABI do you have any any goals
that you've got for this podcast that
you for sure this is this is one and one
link in a chain of initiatives as a
generous term but just things I would
like to see us do that I call share
early share often you know we we have
this kind of default public policy both
internally and externally which loosely
stated means if there is no good reason
to keep something internal or secret or
whatever you know no financials no
personal information or whatever we
should let people see it we should let
people know what's happening and I think
something that we've gotten a little
scared of maybe in the last couple years
as a company and also in our team is is
doing that is sharing things early and
often even when we might be
wrong about something you know just
sharing let's chat about this thing and
figure out if it's worth talking about
or not we're a little bit afraid of
people saying oh okay that means we're
gonna do it or that means they're gonna
do it and it's a terrible idea and I
hate it or whatever instead of just kind
of having a conversation about what's
important what our values are what we
think we need to do what direction we
might want to go in and letting more
people from the community and from the
company be part of those conversations
so that's kind of the share early share
often campaign that I hold near and dear
to my heart and I see this as a really
good opportunity for us to just kind of
informally not really trying to get a
message out there but just show people
kind of what's it like when we get on a
hangout together and talk about
whatever's on our mind whatever the
issue of the day is you know kind of
just like the early early stackoverflow
podcast literally just record our
hangout our meeting as we're trying to
wrestle something through or figure out
what to do next I really love that idea
and I think I hope that the people who
listened to it if they listened to it I
really liked it too yeah that's really
good that's really good I think one of
the things that I'm looking at here in
the future is to be able to to build a
deeper relationship with our users where
it's not just avatar de avatar but where
it's now voice right now people can hear
what we've got what we're thinking about
they can maybe even ask questions
directly we can address some of these
concerns with them just to bring a bring
another level right make make things a
little bit a little bit more human bring
a little more just a little more closely
to that relationship I think it's
important so as we as we discuss what
what our goals are let's let's shift a
little bit into what what our non goals
would be right so what are the things
that we're not wanting to be or to
become by providing this this podcast
Abby let's let's start with you what are
some things that you would say yeah this
this is an on goal yeah it's an on goal
to have this feel like an obligation
have this feel like oh something we got
to do but we don't really have any ideas
we don't have anything to talk about it
it's too much work I don't have time the
the the non goal is to feel like this is
some kind of burden you know it should
be it should be fun for us it should be
useful for us in terms of having the
conversations we need to have as well as
just a super low friction lightweight
way to build that connection more so
it's not you know a super produced super
we
sink time and money and energy into
making this sound perfect it's got to be
just you know have a conversation
hopefully it's interesting have it out
there if people don't like it fine
there'll be another one in a month or
whatever it is so that that's the
biggest one in my mind I think yeah yeah
that's really good and not replacing the
Stack Overflow yeah like yes because
that's great but it's got a much
different scope at this point yeah
different audience different production
values etc yes exactly I have a script
that will hopefully automate the editing
of this stuff and that way it might be
by the time this is out or I might have
died I think an on go for me would be
not to make this some sort of you know
Harvard Journal review type publication
where it's you know all numbers all data
and there's no Humanity in it Oh
for me is to keep things light but yeah
so John we're gonna have to make you
smile more um and I don't know this
might be a problem actually because I
intend to just spout numbers the entire
time so John if you're gonna bring
something to the table if you're gonna
write something down use crayons that's
what I'm gonna know sharpies just bring
your crayons to keep it light keep it
fun all right I'm just gonna scribble my
notes on the back of a newspaper for
this call every time that's the thing
that's the thing I'm into it
I think Comic Sans my new default font
Oprah's horrible so hey real quick what
would be your your favorite site in our
network oh there's a loaded question it
is a loaded question so here listen okay
let's let's uh let's let's make it a
little easier what would be one of your
top ten sites I can
tip my tongue top my mind actually so I
run an internally a weekly segment we
send out a little fireside chat to all
the employees of the company that's got
you know updates and news and there's a
weekly segment on it called the question
of the week and I go around the network
or I take suggestions for a cool
question that's been asked recently
that's a good example of what that site
is about you know it's uploaded it's not
closed
it's got interesting answers and you
know kind of good conversation maybe
presenting a couple different
perspectives I mean I always find myself
going to world building for that say I
have to go back in my notes and say oh
wait I did a world last week fine I'll
try you know some other cool site that
has interesting information and I try to
you know switch off technical and
non-technical but I always go back to
world building man they're so creative
and curious and there's just the the
questions that get asked there even or
like man I don't know if anyone could
possibly answer that and then I eat my
eat my hat or you know stick my foot in
my mouth because I scroll down and
there's 70 great answers you know with
really good theories and ideas so I
always have a good time when I go over
there alright so one of the top 10 for a
B is world building John what about you
well so there is one site on the network
that will always have my my heart and
that is the biblical hermeneutics site
and I don't know how many people know
this but I was a beta user on Stack
Overflow and then I quit I was like I've
had enough of this like voting is
terrible because there's all these awful
incentives and it makes people you know
write stuff that's you know not high
quality I was like this is this is lame
I'm quitting this site and then I kind
of got sucked back in a little bit with
the philosophy site because I thought
that was fun for a few months and then
someone had proposed on area 51 a
biblical hermeneutics site and I I loved
doing Bible studies I I have one every
week in fact on Thursday nights and so I
love doing it and that site just
captured my imagination and I decided I
was going to be the top user on that
site I was going to totally become the
very
best Bible interpreter on that site and
I I went for it and I eventually became
a moderator and so that is easily my
favorite site and I've left so many
questions and answers on that site that
I'm constantly getting pinged from these
old things I wrote and wrote around this
time of year there's just before
Christmas when we're recording there are
questions that relate to the Christmas
story that that I asked and I get
answers to them which is great it's it's
a lot of fun to see that that people are
still engaged with my content from yours
yeah it's pretty awesome so we've got
world-building biblical hermeneutics
yeah what's here's one that's great mine
is I mean near and dear to my heart will
always be Stack Overflow and Hispaniola
oh that's my yeah that's that's my baby
right there I love that site and so for
those of you who don't know I came I
came to stack overflow with with the
intention and for the purpose of
building that site of creating it you
know managing it and it's the site is
graduated it's doing well it's it's I
think it's in our top five of our
network sites yeah I mean it's just it's
it's move-in it's and you know for a
good reason right there's so many people
who speak Spanish and yeah it's great so
that's the site that I really really
like I will always visit it even if I
don't understand my moral I'm I'm a
little more like Gaby than I am John
here in this regard that the technical
stuff tends to baffle me so I use
crayons all the time you know I'm asking
John to bring his crayons just so you
know for my sake but yeah I'm using
crayons and I say yeah so I you know I
try to read as much as I can I'm really
hanging out more on the meta site of
that of that of that community anyway
but yeah it's just really good people
are people doesn't matter what the topic
is we're gonna be able to find something
in common and and work together to build
a stronger community so so when a
Spanish site graduated did you purchase
a mission accomplished banner to put
[Music]
what mission accomplished yeah yeah
that's a good point yeah yeah mission
completed there you go
no I did what I did is I had some
posters made that would that we
distribute it and we put them up in
different universities and things
advertising the site like hey we're here
you know come learn how to code you know
I get your get your answers to the
questions that you've got and so yeah we
did that but no there wasn't anything as
a matter of fact I did get a little
hacky sack from a user yeah a little I
mean that's what I call this yeah yeah
same a little smiley face on it for the
colors of the site which is yellow and
so this thing has been it's been with me
for yeah for many years I love that I
hope that user is is listening out there
and knows those how meaningful a little
hole smiley face hacky sack guy is yeah
me too me too me too
well awesome well as we as we continue
talking about this your podcast
are we in competition with anyone I mean
do you guys feel like we're gonna be
wrestling any feathers with the
character we're gonna be creating our
podcast you mean yeah our podcast
I can imagine us ruffling jay Dalls jay
Hamlin's feathers because he really
liked me podcast and as we know that's
on hiatus and so I think once he gets
wind of this he might be a little
jealous that we didn't invite him on
maybe we should invite him on one of
these should maybe we should yeah maybe
he could be a guest him as a guest Joel
David the whole stackoverflow podcast
gang we can say look come hang out over
here it's a lot easier takes a lot less
time it is it is that's what I'm most
excited about what about you can you
think of any
I don't think cereal is quaking in their
boots right now I our audience is going
to be be much smaller and and that's
fine because we have a very specific
group of people that we want to talk to
and that's our it's our super engaged
users you know right you know they're
often moderators are very heavily
involved in moderator activities on on
other sites you know on all sorts of our
sites and so those are the folks I
really want to talk to and I can give up
being a famous podcaster if we're able
to to talk to the people that we want to
talk to and and hear from them and
hopefully that's you that we're talking
to
yeah yeah I think the the the peak
potential audience for us for this
podcast is I would put it somewhere
around 700 people maybe you know
thinking negative moderators and around
the network and then a few other folks
but we're not going for broad interest
here we're going for in-depth you know
if you're curious about what we talk
about what we're thinking about what
might be coming down the pike or
whatever we want to want to give you
that insight and also hear from you
maybe I think you know what would you
like us to touch on what are you curious
about what have we been weirdly cagey
about that maybe we can provide provide
some insight into maybe we can't also
you know but yeah that's where what
we're really going for it I'm psyched
about it well the reason go go ahead
John also I hope my mom will listen 801
you gotta make mom proud so the reason
why I'm asking if we're gonna have any
kind of any kind of enemies or if you
guys see any of that coming down it's
just simply because we don't want to we
don't want to get in the way of our
advertisers right and the big bucks are
gonna be paying us to produce the show
oh yeah so we don't want to have a
conflict of interest here and we really
want to keep things as tight as we can
and so I know we've got a few
advertisers already coming in John is
the one who's typically responds to
these John we have any of those yeah we
did get a big truck of money that came
and backed up headquarters and it was
from the ask a question wizard and the
reason they wanted to advertise right
now is because it's a new initiative
it's well we've been working on it for a
while but it's finally going into
testing we're gonna send it to new users
about half of the new users who ask a
question will see this and it's a guided
way of asking questions of just getting
this box with with you know nothing in
it and you have to fill in okay what's
my title what are my tags this is a
guided approach and it goes through step
by step in a way that we think
replicates the way that good questions
are asked on the site and so hopefully
we'll have more good questions and yeah
anyway asked question wizard let's spend
a lot of money to get this little blurb
in so I might as well say it that's
truckload of money truckload of my
that's good we need we need pictures or
it didn't happen yeah I think it was a
Tonka truck but it was a truckload of
money so that's great it was a Tonka
truck with the chocolate with the
chocolate coins works like contractor
than a bitch instead of just vaguely
saying truck loads of money we might
actually need a dollar will have to talk
to market yeah well with that let's go
ahead and end our first episode thank
you all so much for for for joining us
and listening in we do look forward to
hearing from you
we're gonna have more announcements and
more features coming up in the future
but I hope to see you all in the next
episode yeah looking forward to it
sounds great thanks y'all bye bye gang
[Music]